Maxine Bartow Papers
© 2002 University of Connecticut
Maxine Bartow Papers.
1958-1991.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Bartow, Maxine.
.15 linear feet
Maxine Bartow and Fielding Dawson, both authors, had a brief romance from March through May of 1959. The friendship between the two continued despite their separation and marriages to other people in the early 1960s, as demonstrated by the correspondence from Dawson. Also included is the manuscript of a short story by Dawson and the proofs of several of his publications. Two photographs, taken in 1958, are also in the collection.
MSS20020140
Biography
Macine Bartow, an author, was an editor at Reader's Digest.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence from Fielding Dawson to Maxine Bartow from 1959 through 1990. Also included are jacket proofs from several Dawson publications, two black and white photographs (1958), the manuscript of a short story, "Her Royal," written by Dawson, and several collections of poems by Robert Creeley.
Arrangement
The collection has been organized into three sections, determined by the format of the materials: Correspondence, Publications and Photographs.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to literature, especially Black Mountain College and the individuals with which it is associated, in addition to a significant collection of Little Magazines. See especially the Papers of Charles Olson, Fielding Dawson, Joel Oppenheimer, Robert Creeley, Ed Dorn, and Gregory Corso. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
Monographs and magazines have been removed from the collection and will be cataloged. Call numbers and locations will be provided in the Library's online catalog, HOMER.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Maxine Bartow in January 2003.
Detailed Description
- Papers,undated, 1958-1991
  - Correspondence
    - 1959 [Spring/Summer] (Box 1:1)
    - 1959 May - August (Box 1:2)
    - 1962-1990 (Box 1:3)
  - Publications
    - The Black Mountain Book, Brochure and jacket proof, 1991 (Box 1:4)
    - Creeley, Robert TMs poems (carbons), undated (Box 1:9)
    - "Her Royal", TMS with corrections, 1989 November (Box 1:5)
    - The Trick: New Stories, jacket proof, undated (Box 1:6)
    - Witness, jacket proof, 1987 Fall (Box 1:7)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs, 1958 (Box 1:8)